<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>ConniePad Blog</title>
        <link>https://doc.conniepad.com/blog</link>
        <description>ConniePad Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New feature: Automatic note history for extra peace of mind!]]></title>
            <link>https://doc.conniepad.com/blog/auto-backup</link>
            <guid>https://doc.conniepad.com/blog/auto-backup</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[I’m excited to introduce a feature that adds an extra layer of protection to your notes — automatic save history! Now, your notes will be captured a snapshot every 5 minutes, so if you accidentally make changes or need to go back to a previous version, you’re covered.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I’m excited to introduce a feature that adds an extra layer of protection to your notes — automatic save history! Now, your notes will be captured a snapshot every 5 minutes, so if you accidentally make changes or need to go back to a previous version, you’re covered.</p>
<p>This feature gives you the peace of mind that your notes are always safe. And as a bonus, it acts as a backup in case iCloud ever fails, ensuring you never lose important information.</p>
<p>Your notes are in good hands—safe, secure, and always recoverable!</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>feature</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New feature: Convert your notes to markdown!]]></title>
            <link>https://doc.conniepad.com/blog/copy-as-markdown</link>
            <guid>https://doc.conniepad.com/blog/copy-as-markdown</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[I’m happy to introduce a handy new feature—now you can easily convert your notes to Markdown format! This makes it super convenient if you want to share your notes with other apps, or use them in automations and shortcuts.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I’m happy to introduce a handy new feature—now you can easily convert your notes to Markdown format! This makes it super convenient if you want to share your notes with other apps, or use them in automations and shortcuts.</p>
<p>With just a few clicks, your notes are transformed into a clean Markdown file, ready for you to send, edit, or integrate wherever you need. Whether you’re working with other note-taking apps or setting up a workflow, this feature helps you move your content smoothly across platforms.</p>
<p>Give it a try and see how Markdown export makes your notes even more versatile!</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>feature</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New feature: Easily embed and resize images!]]></title>
            <link>https://doc.conniepad.com/blog/embed-image</link>
            <guid>https://doc.conniepad.com/blog/embed-image</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[I’m thrilled to announce that adding images to your notes just got a whole lot easier! You can now effortlessly embed multiple images by simply copy-pasting, dragging and dropping, or using the image picker. It’s quick, seamless, and flexible.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I’m thrilled to announce that adding images to your notes just got a whole lot easier! You can now effortlessly embed multiple images by simply copy-pasting, dragging and dropping, or using the image picker. It’s quick, seamless, and flexible.</p>
<p>The best part? The quality of your images is preserved, so your visuals stay sharp. You can also resize images to fit your content perfectly, giving you more control over how your notes look.</p>
<p>Want to get creative? You can nest images within other content, letting you express your ideas in a way that’s clear and visually engaging.</p>
<p>Give it a try and let your notes come to life with images!</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>feature</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Introducing powerful tables: Reorder, merge, and color!]]></title>
            <link>https://doc.conniepad.com/blog/table-drag-and-drop</link>
            <guid>https://doc.conniepad.com/blog/table-drag-and-drop</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[I’m excited to announce a big upgrade to tables in the app! With this new feature, organizing your data is now easier (and more fun) than ever. You can simply drag and drop columns and rows to reorder them however you like—perfect for keeping your info in exactly the right place.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I’m excited to announce a big upgrade to tables in the app! With this new feature, organizing your data is now easier (and more fun) than ever. You can simply drag and drop columns and rows to reorder them however you like—perfect for keeping your info in exactly the right place.</p>
<p>Adding new rows and columns is just as simple. Whether you're expanding your list or reworking a layout, you can quickly insert what you need with a click. And for those moments when you need more flexibility, you can merge cells to create custom layouts that work for your content.</p>
<p>But that’s not all—you can also style individual cells with custom background colors! This makes it easy to visually highlight important sections or organize your data in a way that stands out.</p>
<p>Try it out and make your tables work exactly the way you want. I can’t wait to hear what you think!</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>feature</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Text Highlighting!]]></title>
            <link>https://doc.conniepad.com/blog/support-text-highlighting</link>
            <guid>https://doc.conniepad.com/blog/support-text-highlighting</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[We’ve just added a feature that I think you’re going to love—text highlighting! Now, you can bring even more personality and organization to your notes by adding a splash of color to important sections.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We’ve just added a feature that I think you’re going to love—text highlighting! Now, you can bring even more personality and organization to your notes by adding a splash of color to important sections.</p>
<p>Whether you’re jotting down key ideas, to-do lists, or important reminders, highlighting makes it easier to focus on what really matters. Simply select your text, choose your favorite highlight color, and voilà—your notes are instantly more readable and organized.</p>
<p>This feature fits right in with our mission to make note-taking effortless and enjoyable. So go ahead, give it a try and brighten up your notes! As always, I’d love to hear what you think—your feedback helps make the app even better.</p>
<p>Happy highlighting!</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>feature</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why do I made note app]]></title>
            <link>https://doc.conniepad.com/blog/welcome</link>
            <guid>https://doc.conniepad.com/blog/welcome</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[I'm Huy, the developer & founder of ConniePad. I know everyone has the same question: with so many note apps out there, why did I make this one? The answer is I struggle to find any app that is lightweight, has a comprehensive formatting editor, works offline, ensures privacy for enterprise usage, has lifetime price model, and is compatible with the collaboration tools I use every day, such as Jira, Confluence, and Trello.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I'm Huy, the developer &amp; founder of ConniePad. I know everyone has the same question: with so many note apps out there, why did I make this one? The answer is <strong>I struggle to find any app that is lightweight, has a comprehensive formatting editor, works offline, ensures privacy for enterprise usage, has lifetime price model, and is compatible with the collaboration tools I use every day, such as Jira, Confluence, and Trello.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Firstly, my ideal note app must have an easy-to-use editor and formatting system</strong>. I can't remember <a href="https://www.markdownguide.org/basic-syntax/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Markdown</a> syntax, don't use <a href="https://git-scm.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Git</a> to backup my notes, and don't know how to customise style with <a href="https://web.dev/learn/css" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">CSS</a>. If you don't know what those are, no worries—they're for developers. What you should care about is there are buttons to toggle bold, italic, underline, buttons to insert, resize, change tables, layouts, and expandable sections, and be able to drag and drop images, videos, and links into notes.</p>
<p>( To all my dev friends, don't worry, I'll hide advanced features in the config. We're good at finding hidden things like that ;) )</p>
<p><strong>As an Apple fan, I believe the app should work offline, be smooth, and be native on macOS</strong>. Any delay could prevent me from capturing important information that quickly passes through my brain. I believe that multi-platform apps mean no platform is perfect. It consumes more memory, battery and lack deep integration with the OS. Since I'm not a Window, Linux, or Android user, I focus my efforts on making the app work best and integrate well with the features that the Apple ecosystem offers.</p>
<p>We not only take notes for personal life but also for work, business, and sensitive data. It's risky and often against company policies to store work data with 3rd-party vendors, where it can be accessed by others, to sell for ads or used for AI training. That's why I designed an app that saves notes in files and folders system on your disk - <strong>privacy-first</strong>. This familiar system lets you choose how you want to back up and sync your data, or you can let Apple iCloud handle it if you prefer.</p>
<p><strong>This note formatting is compatible with <a href="https://www.atlassian.com/software/jira" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Jira</a>, <a href="https://www.atlassian.com/software/confluence" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Confluence</a>, <a href="https://trello.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Trello</a>, and <a href="https://bitbucket.org/product" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Bitbucket</a></strong>—the leading work management and collaboration tools used by world-class companies like Apple, Tesla, Reddit, Canva, Mercedes-Benz, and NASA.</p>
<p>In my opinion, <strong>an ideal personal note app should offer a lifetime license instead of a subscription</strong>. Take Evernote as an example: users' data is held hostage, and they have to pay continuously increasing prices until they can't afford it and must find an alternative solution. Subscription models are great for low-entry trials, but when you commit to storing your personal knowledge for years, it's like entering into a rental agreement with a landlord—you could be evicted anytime. They might offer a free plan, but maintaining a free plan is a cost for them and could be cut at any time.</p>
<p><strong>They can’t afford to offer a lifetime license, but my app can due to the technology I use, which gives me an advantage to offer my users a lifetime deal—unlimited usage without breaking the bank</strong>. Currently, I offer the app for $19.99 on the Mac App Store, which you can purchase once and use forever, for many years. If you do some research, you’ll find this is significantly cheaper than other competitors, which cost you $50-$150 yearly. This is a limited offer as a thank you to everyone who supports me in this early stage. I will eventually have a trial version if you want to try it before committing to buy, but the lifetime price won’t be $19.99 anymore.</p>
<p>If your company has <strong>Apple Business Management</strong> or your university has <strong>Apple School Management</strong>, you can <strong>get the app for free</strong>. Please contact your admin.</p>
<p>Remember that <strong>this app may be tax deductible</strong> in some countries, as you could claim it as a tool to generate your income. Seek advice from your accountant.</p>
<p>Thanks for reading this, and I really appreciate your time. The app still has many areas to improve, and I will push it forward every day. If you have any questions, feedback, or would like to connect, feel free to drop an email to <strong><a href="mailto:huy@conniepad.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">huy@conniepad.com</a></strong>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>